Ashwani Kumar V

Senior DevOps Engineer

- **** +91 7989 121 975
- ✓ avardhineni7@gmail.com
- ♥ Hyderabad, IN
- in linkedin.com/in/avk-sd
- github.com/SimplifiedDevOps

SUMMARY

9+ years of experience in IT field which includes 6+ years in handling AWS Cloud environments, Build and Administer Micro-Services architecture through Kubernetes and AWS EKS.

Proficiency in working in DevOps lifecycle management environment, creating build & release pipelines, Infrastructure Automation & Configuration Management in multiple environments.

Analytical, committed, persistent individual and reliable team member. Continuously learning and acquiring new knowledge and skills.

KEY SKILLS

Linux/UNIX Administration Bash Scripting, Python Scripting **Windows Server Operating Systems** AWS Cloud, Boto3 AWS Security, DevSecOps Terraform Ansible, Packer Git/Git Hub, Bitbucket, Code Commit Maven, JFrog, Sonarqube Jenkins, CodeBuild, CICD Integration Docker, CodeDeploy Kubernetes, AWS EKS Helm Charts, CodePipeline AWS Lambda, API Gateway Prometheus & Grafana CloudWatch, JIRA

AWS Cloud Administration, Terraform & Ansible Automation, Kubernetes Admin with DevOps Lifecycle

Professional Experience

Senior Cloud Engineer, Visionet Systems Pvt. Ltd. Bengaluru Date: July 2021 – Till date

Job Profile: Build and Release Management, Deployment Automation, and Kubernetes Administration.

Cloud Engineer, TCS, Hyderabad

Payroll: Ivytel Technologies Pvt. Ltd. Bengaluru,

Date: January 2018 - July 2021

Job Profile: AWS Administration & DevOps Engineer

Module Lead, Mindtree LTD. Hyderabad,
Date: February 2015 – December 2017
Job Profile: AWS Administration & Infrastructure Automation

Employment History

Roles and Responsibilities

- 1. Responsible for **fault-tolerance**, **high-availability**, **scalability** and **security** on AWS Infrastructure and platform.
- 2. Good understanding and implementation of **Microservices Concepts** and **Best Practices**.
- 3. Responsible for **Integration of CI/CD Pipelines** with automated build and test systems.
- 4. Responsible for **Production Deployment** using **Multiple Deployment** Strategies.
- 5. **Automating the AWS Infrastructure** and Platform Deployment with Infrastructure as a Code.
- 6. Build and maintain tools for **deployment**, **monitoring** and operations.
- 7. Support and **troubleshoot scalability**, **high availability**, performance, **monitoring**, **backup and restoration** of different environments.
- 8. Able to **carry out POCs** to make sure that suggested design technologies meet the requirements.
- 9. Evaluate **new tools, technologies** and processes to improve the speed, efficiency and **scalability of CI/CD environments**.
- 10. Used **Jira as a Change Management**, Work Management, Scrum Agile tool. Updating the Application team to track the status of User Stories.

Skills and Experience

- 1. Embedding **Security** at every step of SDLC with various **DevSecOps tools**.
- Expertise in deploying at scale, various Containerized web, data and service applications using Docker, Kubernetes, Elastic Kubernetes
 Service (EKS), Elastic Container Services (ECS), CloudWatch, and other monitoring solutions.
- 3. Strong experience in **40+ AWS Cloud Native Services** in Compute, Storage, Database, IAM, Monitoring, Security vectors.

DevSecOps Tools

Git Hooks & Talisman Mutation Tests - PIT SonarQube

Trivy Image Scan

OPA Confest

KubeSec

DAST

OWASAP ZAP

CIS Benchmarking & Kube-Bench

Istio

Kiali

Falco

KubeScan

HashiCorp Vault

EDUCATION

<u>Education History</u>

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Solutions Architect -Associate Hashicorp Certified - Terraform Associate

- Configured AWS Security Services such as IAM, KMS, ACM, WAF, Inspector, Trusted Advisor, Cloud Trail and Guard Duty to secure resources at multiple layers.
- 5. Used **Terraform to build** multiple environments such as Dev, Staging and Prod using AWS DevOps workflow.
- Standardized the **Terraform modules** for all the resources in AWS Cloud. This helped in **reducing the code time** and re-usability of the modules.
- 7. Automated the **creation of Golden AMI** through Packer and used **Ansible for Application Configuration.**
- 8. Extensively **used Ansible** to **install and configure** all the DevOps tools. Also **Dynamically configured the inventory file** to avoid manual input of IP address in the host file.
- 9. Used Jenkins Pipelines to integrate all Micro Services builds out to the Docker/ECR registry and then deployed to Kubernetes/ECS/EKS, and managed the application with various Kubernetes Objects also integrated with Jira and Slack to send build state information.
- 10. **Optimize Jenkins container** Configurations such as mount docker runtime inside container as a volume, fixing permissions on docker.sock, and **scripted Jenkins configurations** in to a Jenkinsfile to run Single Pipeline and MultiBranch Pipeline jobs.
- 11. Experience in administrating Kubernetes and a good understanding of manifest management with Helm along with expertise in Ingress Controller and Service mesh with Istio for Pod Communication and Encryption.
- 12. Used **Terraform to automate** the EKS Cluster and **integrated Terraform in CI/CD Pipelines** to automate provisioning of Servers.
- 13. **Automated tasks** such as System Checks, Adding Tags, Monitoring and Remote Administration, Backup and Restore, Scheduled tasks, Clean-up, Data Visualizations, Send Notifications, CI/CD related tasks **through Python Scripting**.
- 14. **Configured ELK/EFK ElasticStack** for deep search and data analytics, fluentD for centralized logging, log enrichment and parsing and Kibana for powerful and beautiful data visualizations.
- 15. Used **Jira as Change Management** and **Scrum Agile tool**. Updating the applications team in order to track the status of the user stories and defects.
- 16. Configured Prometheus Server and its components such as Grafana, Alert Manager, ServiceMonitor, Prometheus Rules to monitor all Cluster Nodes, K8S Components, Microservices Applications and Redis Data broker.
- 17. **Successfully upgraded** the Kubernetes and Jenkins by following the best practices and effective took the **backup of ETCD** database and performed timely restore drills.
- 18. **Performed Cost Optimization** with Kubecost to avoid overspending on the resources.

Looking Forward To Learn

- 1. Azure Cloud, Azure DevOps
- 2. GCP
- 3. CKA Certification
- 4. New DevOps and DevSecOps tools that emerge during my DevOps Engineer Journey.